<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Beneath Abstraction</title><link>https://gopkumr.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Beneath Abstraction</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 10:51:44 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gopkumr.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>ASP.Net MVC 5 and Security</title><link>https://gopkumr.github.io/post/mvc5security/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 10:51:44 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://gopkumr.github.io/post/mvc5security/</guid><description>Security? Security is one of the most important cross-cutting concern for any web application. All applications (except for static web sites) require to identify a user and restrict the users from viewing or performing actions on pages.
Authentication Authentication is the method by which an application identifies a user. By identifying a user, the application can decide whether the user is a valid user to access the application.
Authorization Authorization is the way the application decides if the identified user can view a particular page or perform a particular action.</description></item><item><title>Clean your code using Code cleanup in Visual Studio 2019</title><link>https://gopkumr.github.io/post/codecleanup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 14:22:48 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://gopkumr.github.io/post/codecleanup/</guid><description>All we developers would have spent time in cleaning up the code after we are done with a long day of code and coffee! for .Net developers it is to do with removing all the using clause added automatically by visual studio/nuget that you no longer need, removing variables that was not put to use, adding read only to eligible private variables, adding or removing braces from single statement blocks etc etc.</description></item></channel></rss>