<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>OAuth on Beneath Abstraction</title>
    <link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/tags/oauth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OAuth on Beneath Abstraction</description>
    <image>
      <title>Beneath Abstraction</title>
      <url>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/images/logo.png</url>
      <link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/images/logo.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.152.2</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 19:23:15 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.beneathabstraction.com/tags/oauth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Securely calling Azure API from PowerApp Portal</title>
      <link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/powerportalapicall/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 19:23:15 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/powerportalapicall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;context&#34;&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Powerapps Portal gives a quick and easy way to build public facing websites. Data in the portal is mostly fetched from Microsoft Dataverse using Powerplatform FetchXML or the portal&amp;rsquo;s Web API. These operations are secured using portal&amp;rsquo;s application session, as explained &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/power-apps/maker/portals/web-api-overview&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Often there are requirements to consume an externally hosted API, in this particular example an API hosted in Azure behind an API Management. With Javascript the only option to trigger an API, implementing a secret based authentication is out of scope. But there is an alternate approach.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identity in Microsoft Azure - Modern Authentication</title>
      <link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/securingusingazure-part2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Aug 2021 18:06:02 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/securingusingazure-part2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Continuing from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.beneathabstraction.com/content/post/securingusingazure-part1&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;, the new generation of authentication mechanism was created to satisfy the new generation of application, starting from apps that run just in the browser to apps that run on micro-controllers. This new generation of authentication mechanism called as the modern authentication protocols are built on top of the OAuth protocol and taking inspiration from SAML.
In the below article the term IDP refers to the Identity provider, the external service that is responsible for authenticating a user and issuing authorization tokens. This service is both trusted by the client app as well as the resource api.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identity in Microsoft Azure - A bit of history</title>
      <link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/securingusingazure-part1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 19:16:16 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/securingusingazure-part1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authentication has been an important component in the world of IT from the time companies required their employees to prove their identity to use the company&amp;rsquo;s computing resources whether it was to execute its business processes or accessing email or file. During the earlier days employees used to login to their computers using a username and password, which was stored in a central server like an active directory (in case of Microsoft tech stack). With the active directory credentials employees where able to use to login to both their windows computers as well as the email application both of which were in the same network. This approach worked well for many years until the softwares and services that the companies used where no longer within their network.&lt;br&gt;
While active directory protocols like NTLM or Kerberos could work across external networks via technologies like VPN it was complex to setup and maintain such an infrastructure while keeping all the connection secure and stable. Also with growing number of users/services and the pace at which the growth occurred, these technologies were not designed to scale at that pace. Hence new Authentication mechanisms were needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
