<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>azure on Beneath Abstraction</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/tags/azure/</link><description>Recent content in azure on Beneath Abstraction</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 19:16:16 +1000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.beneathabstraction.com/tags/azure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Identity in Microsoft Azure - A bit of history</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/securingusingazure-part1/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 19:16:16 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/securingusingazure-part1/</guid><description>Introduction Authentication has been an important component in the world of IT from the time companies required their employees to prove their identity to use the company&amp;rsquo;s computing resources whether it was to execute its business processes or accessing email or file. During the earlier days employees used to login to their computers using a username and password, which was stored in a central server like an active directory (in case of Microsoft tech stack).</description></item><item><title>Cloud Resume Challenge - Azure Serverless</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/azureserverlessresume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 10:18:48 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/azureserverlessresume/</guid><description>I recently came across the site https://cloudresumechallenge.dev/ and decided to give it a try using Azure services. To start simple I decided to ignore the DB, CDN part etc and just have the the UI and the middler layer of the app. Below is the high level architecture.
The front end of the app will be hosted a static web site in Azure Blob storage. Backend will be an Azure function that will feed the resume data to the frontend over HTTP, the azure function will be a HTTP triggered function.</description></item><item><title>Implementing Custom Feature flags - Your own logic to shutoff a feature - Azure App Configuration</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/azurecustomfeatureflags/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 10:18:48 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/azurecustomfeatureflags/</guid><description>This is a continuation from the previous article on feature flags implemented using Azure App configuration service to maintain the flags. Just to reiterate, feature management can be implemented using config files but this article is trying to implement feature flags connecting to Azure App configuration service.
Introduction The previous article described about implementing a boolean feature flag to turn on/off a feature. In this article I am trying to implement a custom feature flag.</description></item><item><title>Implementing Feature flags using azure</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/azurefeatureflags/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 May 2021 10:00:48 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/azurefeatureflags/</guid><description>Feature flag is a very popular practice in modern application development, which is used to specifically hide features implemented that are not yet ready to be used by wider audience, and when ready can be enabled by a flip of a switch. The flags can also be used as a kill switch for application feature when it not working as expected.
With feature flags implemented, it would be effective to have the features enabled or disabled from a location outside of the application infrastructure or configuration, this way we can have features spanning across applications be controlled via a centralized flag.</description></item><item><title>Azure for integration and process automation</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/azureintegration/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 18:52:19 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/azureintegration/</guid><description>Problem Businesses run on multiple applications and services, how well the business runs is often impacted on how efficiently data is distributed to the correct task. Automating this flow of data is a way to streamline the business. The problem here is to choose the right technology for this data integration and process automation.
Objective This article is describing the azure technologies that are available during time of writing to solve the business need.</description></item></channel></rss>