<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>c# on Beneath Abstraction</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/tags/c#/</link><description>Recent content in c# on Beneath Abstraction</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-au</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 10:18:48 +1100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.beneathabstraction.com/tags/c#/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Resume Challenge - Azure Serverless</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/azureserverlessresume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jun 2021 10:18:48 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/azureserverlessresume/</guid><description>I recently came across the site https://cloudresumechallenge.dev/ and decided to give it a try using Azure services. To start simple I decided to ignore the DB, CDN part etc and just have the the UI and the middler layer of the app. Below is the high level architecture.
The front end of the app will be hosted a static web site in Azure Blob storage. Backend will be an Azure function that will feed the resume data to the frontend over HTTP, the azure function will be a HTTP triggered function.</description></item><item><title>Implementing Custom Feature flags - Your own logic to shutoff a feature - Azure App Configuration</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/azurecustomfeatureflags/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 10:18:48 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/azurecustomfeatureflags/</guid><description>This is a continuation from the previous article on feature flags implemented using Azure App configuration service to maintain the flags. Just to reiterate, feature management can be implemented using config files but this article is trying to implement feature flags connecting to Azure App configuration service.
Introduction The previous article described about implementing a boolean feature flag to turn on/off a feature. In this article I am trying to implement a custom feature flag.</description></item><item><title>Radio Player using Blazor 5</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/blazor5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 16:35:28 +1000</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/blazor5/</guid><description>I have been reading the Blazor 5 documentation and decided to create a simple project to give its features a try. As always, there were a ton of ideas in my mind but while scanning through dev.to i came across a post by Aleks Popovic, where he made a Radio player using react, so i decided to create one using Blazor 5. I used the same service as Aleks to get the radio stations, called the Radio-Browser.</description></item><item><title>Infrastructure as C#</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/infraascsharp/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 18:52:19 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/infraascsharp/</guid><description>Introduction After attempting the .Net tutorial on deploying a simple WebAPI based microservice to Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS), wanted a better way to represent my infrastructure than the YAML.xml file. This was partly because of me being novice in YAML format and partly to have a way to abstract the infrastructure in order to make it repeatable and it should be not just confined to AKS. The first solution to this problem was to use a framework like Terraform to define my infrastructure as code.</description></item><item><title>Steps for Deploying a Blazor as Static Site with Docker and Nginx</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/blazorhostdocker/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 18:52:19 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/blazorhostdocker/</guid><description>Step 1 Publish the Blazor WebAssembly project Publish the project from Visual Studio,this ensures that the projects is linked which removes all the unwanted dependencies from the output, reducing the size of the assemblies created.
Step 2 Create a dockerfile The docker file is very straightforward, pull the nginx image and copy the published Blazor WebAssembly file from the WWWRoot folder to the html folder in nginx
FROM nginx:alpine EXPOSE 80 COPY bin/Release/netcoreapp3.</description></item><item><title>Hosting Blazor WebAssembly on ASP.Net Core WebAPI</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/blazorhostwebapi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Jun 2020 18:52:19 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/blazorhostwebapi/</guid><description>Background My WebAssembly project has now been configured to be a PWA (refer the previous article in series). It time to introduce hosting. Since the WebAssembly project handles the client side, I want it to be unchanged but be hosted it in a project that can be used as backend for the UI, hence chose WebAPI.
The Changes Create a new solution and add the already created Blazor WebAssembly project Add a new ASPNet core web project and choose WebAPI template and call it the .</description></item><item><title>How can I turn my Blazor WebAssembly to PWA?</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/blazorwasntopwa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 18:52:19 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/blazorwasntopwa/</guid><description>Lets get started with an existing Blazor WebAssembly project I already have a Blazor WebAssembly project created implementing Angular Tour of heros application. You can find the project in my GitHub repository here Repo: https://github.com/gopkumr/BlazorTourOfHeroes.git Branch: Release
Next step is making this into PWA As with any web application, adding PWA capabilities to Blazor follows the web standard process of adding a manifest json file and the service workers js file.</description></item><item><title>An attempt to convert Blazor WebAssembly Project to Blazor Server App</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/blazorwebasmtoserv/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2020 18:52:19 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/blazorwebasmtoserv/</guid><description>Blazor Web-Assembly Project This starts from my Blazor Web-Assembly project that I create as a replica of the Angular TourOfHeros tutorial. The source code of project is in GitHub
This is an attempt to convert the existing project to a Blazor server app with few changes to the wiring up and hosting configuration. Since this article is written with a pre-release version of Blazor Web-Assembly, there could be changes to the steps after the actual release expected in May 2020.</description></item><item><title>a sneak peek into Blazor WebAssembly</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/introblazor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 18:52:19 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/introblazor/</guid><description>an attempt to create tour of heroes&amp;rsquo; using Blazor preface WebAssembly is an exciting piece of software, along with HTML, CSS and JavaScript WebAssembly (or WASM) is the fourth language that modern browsers can run natively, WASM is run in the browser in the same security sandbox as the JavaScript frameworks run. WASM also lets you invoke JavaScript and vice versa, making it coexist with JavaScript, More on WebAssembly here: https://webassembly.</description></item><item><title>ASP.Net MVC 5 and Security</title><link>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/mvc5security/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 10:51:44 +1100</pubDate><guid>https://www.beneathabstraction.com/post/mvc5security/</guid><description>Security? Security is one of the most important cross-cutting concern for any web application. All applications (except for static web sites) require to identify a user and restrict the users from viewing or performing actions on pages.
Authentication Authentication is the method by which an application identifies a user. By identifying a user, the application can decide whether the user is a valid user to access the application.
Authorization Authorization is the way the application decides if the identified user can view a particular page or perform a particular action.</description></item></channel></rss>